当我们讨论工业型机器人时，描述方向很重要
When we're discussing industrial type robots, it's important to describe the orientation
末端执行器，夹子-通过拾取完成工作的机器人的一部分
of the end effector, the gripper - the piece of the robot that does the work by picking
将物体放下并放下。这类机器人的常见惯例是什么
objects up and putting them down. The common convention in this type of robotics is what's
称为2轴表示。我们首先定义一个名为the的向量
called the 2-axis representation. We start off by defining a vector which is called the
接近矢量，这是与机器人手指平行的矢量。我们定义
approach vector and that's the vector that's parallel to the fingers of the robot. We define
另一个我们称之为方向向量的向量，它是连接的向量
another vector which we call the orientation vector and that's the vector that joins the
两根手指的提示。所以这说明了机器人手指的扭曲
tips of two fingers. So that says something about the twist of the robot fingers around
方法向量。对于很多机器人操作任务，只需了解方法即可
the approach vector. And for a lot of robotic manipulation tasks, just knowing the approach
矢量和方向矢量足以能够描述夹具的方向。
vector and the orientation vector is sufficient to be able to describe the orientation of the gripper.
为了创建一个右手坐标系，我们引入了一个刚刚调用的第三个向量
In order to create a right-handed coordinate frame we introduce a third vector just called
法向量。现在我们可以将夹具的方向表示为正交
the normal vector. Now we can express the orientation of the gripper as an orthonormal
旋转矩阵。我们通过将N向量，O向量和向量堆叠为列来实现
rotation matrix. We do that by stacking up as columns the N vector, the O vector and
A矢量。我们可以将其扩展为3x3矩阵，每列都是元素
the A vector. We're can expand this out as a 3 x 3 matrix and each column are the elements
N，O和A向量。所有这些列必须是正交的。所以，如果我们知道A和
of the N, O and A vectors. All of these columns must be orthogonal. So if we know the A and
在O向量中，我们可以计算N向量作为O和A向量的叉积。
the O vector, we can compute the N vector as the cross product of the O and the A vector.
这里简要回顾一下与正交矩阵相关的规则。一点
Here's a quick recap on the rules that relate the columns of an orthogonal matrix. A little
我用来帮助记忆的技巧是考虑N，O和A写在圆形上
trick that I use to aid my memory is to consider that N, O and A are written on a circular
条纸。我们从我们想知道的符号开始，并且等于十字架
strip of paper. We start with the symbol that we want to know, and is equal to the cross
围绕圈子的下两个产品。
product of the next two around the circle.
在这里，我有一个非常简单的机器人，我们在这里有我们的世界坐标框架
Here I have a very simple robot and we have our world coordinate frame here, which is
我们对位置和方向的参考。而这个机器人将要拿起这个电池。
our reference for both position and for orientation. And this robot is going to pick up this battery.
为此，我们需要描述夹具的位置和方向。
In order to do that, we need to describe both the position and the orientation of the gripper.
可能是因为我们想要像这样或我们这样的抓手方向拿起电池
It might be that we want to pick up the battery with a gripper orientation like this or we
可能想要像这样的抓手方向拿起电池。无论哪种方式我们都需要
might want to pick up the battery with a gripper orientation like this. Either way we need
能够描述夹具的方向。所以我们做了以前做过的事，
to be able to describe the orientation of the gripper. So we do what we've done before,
与其他对象。我们将坐标框架附加到机器人的抓手上。我们定位
with other objects. We attach a coordinate frame to the gripper of the robot. We orient
它使z轴向外指向。我们将此称为接近向量。它的
it so that the z-axis is pointing outwards. We refer to this as the approach vector. It's
通常是抓手接近物体的方向。我们有另一个向量
generally the direction in which the gripper approaches the object. We have another vector
我们称之为方向矢量，并且与夹具坐标的y轴平行
which we call the orientation vector and is parallel to the y-axis of the gripper's coordinate
框架，这是抓手的方向。我们是否希望抓手的手指像这样
frame and that is the orientation of the gripper. Do we want the gripper's fingers like this
或者像这样。第三个向量，x轴我们称为法向量。
or like this. And the third vector, the x-axis we refer to as the normal vector.